studybass.com 2019-07-06

# StudyBass Privacy Policy

This privacy policy is in effect on and from May 25, 2018.

### General Statement About StudyBass, Data, and Privacy

StudyBass' mission is to teach users about music. It is not in the business of selling or distributing personal data. Data collected by StudyBass is used to aid in the mission of teaching music to its users and improve its product and services for future users.

This privacy policy explains what data StudyBass collects, how it is used, and your rights.

### Who Is StudyBass?

StudyBass is owned and operated by Leading Tone Media, LLC located in Houston, Texas.

Andrew Pouska is the President of Leading Tone Media, LLC, serves as the data protection officer, and may be contacted at any time through this [website's contact form](https://www.studybass.com/feedback/).

### Contacting StudyBass

If you have any questions, problems or need to contact StudyBass regarding this privacy policy or your data, you may do so through the [website contact form](https://www.studybass.com/feedback/).

### Definitions

“ **StudyBass”** and the **“Site”** refer to the website available at studybass.com.

The **“Service”** refers to the interactive features of the website, emails, and newsletters.

“ **Personal Information”** refers to data such as IP address, email address, and name.

“ **User-Created Data”** refers to data a registered user voluntarily inputs into the Site.

“ **User Information”** refers to Personal Information and User-Created Data collectively.

### What Data Does StudyBass Collect?

 **Information you provide to StudyBass**

If a user wishes to use advanced features of the website, a user account must be created. This account requests:

 **Username** – to uniquely identify your account.

 **Email address** – to interact with a user for transactional emails such as password reset requests and other account functions. This email is also used for opt-in newsletters and site updates. StudyBass never signs you up to any emails automatically.

 **First and Last Name** – This makes interactions with the site administrator more personable and human, but is optional—you may use a fake name.

 **Time Zone** – This setting helps StudyBass display dates in a user's local time zone. Optional.

 **Left-hand Orientation** – This is used to display fretboard diagram layouts for left or right hand orientation. Optional.

 **Fretboard Wood** – This is used to adjust a user's diagram color preferences. Optional.

 **Tuning** – This is used to automatically set some StudyBass features to a user's preferred tuning and number of strings. Optional.

Users may create data ("User-Created Data") on StudyBass as part of the Service. These data include, but are not limited to, lesson completion history, favorites, practice routines, practice history and lesson notes. This data is not shared outside of StudyBass. It may be accessed by a StudyBass administrator for troubleshooting, testing or improving the Service.

 **Information StudyBass collects automatically**

 **Server Log Files** – When you visit a website the web server logs some basic information. This may include IP addresses, browser type, ISP referring/exit pages, operating system, and date/time stamps. 

**Login Time** – StudyBass stores your last login time.

 **Cookies** – StudyBass may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears automatically after you close your browser. A persistent cookie, such as a “Remember Me” cookie, remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Website. Please see StudyBass' detailed cookie policy.

 **Data Analytics**

StudyBass collects anonymized statistics about how users use the Site. Anonymized means a user's exact IP address is not logged. Examples of statistical data includes user screen size or pages visited. This data is used to help improve the function and use of the Site.

StudyBass uses a private analytics software package. This data is only used for internal purposes and is not shared with other parties.

 **Information StudyBass does NOT collect**

StudyBass does not collect, receive or store any financial information such as credit card numbers or wallet information.

StudyBass does not ask for, or want, from its users any Sensitive Personal Data such as racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data, data concerning health or data concerning a natural person's sex life or sexual orientation. StudyBass further recommends not sharing this data anywhere on the internet unless absolutely necessary.

### Third-Party Services

#### What are Third-Party Services?

Third-Party Services are external services used by the Site which provide added functionality to the Site. These third-party services may collect some information, such as IP address, from your visit to this site and possibly connect it to information from other sites you visit using the same services. For example, watching YouTube videos on different websites, YouTube could be aware that they were watched by the same user.

#### What types of third-party services does StudyBass use?

 **Email Services**

These services help in the smooth, trusted delivery of email and protect users from spam.  
StudyBass uses Mailgun to deliver transactional email and newsletters. Read [Mailgun's Privacy Policy](https://www.mailgun.com/privacy-policy).

StudyBass uses ProtonMail for other emails between administrators and users.

 **Ad Networks**

To help support the Site, StudyBass uses popular advertising networks. These ad networks use cookies and may track you across other websites on the internet. StudyBass supporting members are not shown these ads. With enough direct support from users StudyBass won't need these ad networks.

StudyBass uses [Google Adsense](https://www.google.com/adsense/) and [Amazon CPM Ads](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=468496).

Third party vendors, including Google and Amazon, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to this website and other websites.   
Users may opt out of Google's personalized advertising by visiting [Google's Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).  
Users can opt out of many other ad networks personalized advertising by visiting [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

 **Affiliate Marketing**

Affiliate marketing lets websites earn commissions from sales of products it recommends and links at no extra cost to the buyer.

These affiliate marketers use cookies to track your purchases to give referring sites their commission.

StudyBass partners with [Conversant](https://www.cj.com/) affiliate marketing.

And, we are a participant in the [Amazon Services LLC Associates Program](https://affiliate-program.amazon.com/), an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

 **Content Delivery Networks**

Content delivery networks (CDNs) host site content such as videos, audio files, pdfs and images. They ensure faster and smoother delivery of this content. These CDNs may log user information such as IP addresses.

StudyBass uses [Amazon Web Services](https://aws.amazon.com/) and [Rackspace Cloud Files](https://www.rackspace.com/cloud/files).

 **Code Libraries**

A common practice on the internet is to use centralized code libraries. Websites work faster by not downloading the same code libraries, such as jQuery, again and again from each individual site. Instead, a central site is used and shared among thousands of websites. Therefore, when you visit a website you likely have a cached copy of some of the code. Your web browser doesn't need to download the code again. It saves bandwidth and speeds up the page load time.

Hosts of these code libraries may or may not collect information such as IP addresses accessing the code libraries. StudyBass does not share any Personal Information with these sites.  

 **Video Streaming Services**

 ****StudyBass uses embedded video streaming services such as YouTube.

These services can collect your video viewing and IP address. StudyBass does not share any Personal Information with these video streaming services. ****

 **Payment Processors**

 ****StudyBass uses PayPal as a payment processor for donations and to collect payments for extra features such as memberships and account add-ons.

When users kindly donate to or support StudyBass through PayPal, PayPal may share information such as your name, email address, or mailing address with StudyBass. This information may be connected to your StudyBass account if necessary to provide the Service the user has purchased. ****

### Email Communications

 **Transactional Emails**  
From time to time we may email you information about StudyBass that we think is necessary and important. By opening or maintaining an account with StudyBass, you agree to receive administrative emails as part of your basic service. Non-administrative emails all require you to opt-in and opting-out is easy.

 **Opt-in Newsletter**  
If you choose, StudyBass will send occasional newsletters to your account email address. Subscribing to the newsletter has always been and will always be opt-in. You can change your newsletter preferences and email address in your [StudyBass User Account Settings](https://www.studybass.com/user/).  
StudyBass collects statistics about email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help monitor and improve newsletter. 

**Private Emails**  
If you write to StudyBass for support, questions, or other matters, StudyBass will store, use and reply to these emails for troubleshooting problems, improving site features, fixing bugs, promotional testimonials (with your explicit permission), to thank you, or to contact you in regards to your musical development. Your email address will not be added to any email lists.

### How Does StudyBass Use Your Data?

StudyBass uses your data to provide the Site's Service. The Service includes features which allow users to log their lesson progress and history, create and record practice sessions, and create user notes. This user created data is not shared with third-parties. StudyBass may use this data internally to improve the Service.

### Who Can See Your Data?

StudyBass does not sell, rent access to, or distribute User-Created Data or Personal Information to third-parties. Site administrators have access to your data.  
Your data is not displayed to the public on the Site.

### What is the Lawful Basis for Processing Personal Information?

We may Process your Personal Information where: you have given your consent; the Processing is necessary for a contract between you and us; the Processing is required by applicable law; the Processing is necessary to protect the vital interests of any individual; or where we have a valid legitimate interest in the Processing.

In Processing your User Information in connection with the purposes set out in this Policy, we may rely on one or more of the following legal bases, depending on the circumstances:

  * Consent: We may Process your User Information where we have obtained your prior, express consent to the Processing (this legal basis is only used in relation to Processing that is entirely voluntary – it is not used for Processing that is necessary or obligatory in any way);
  * Contractual necessity: We may Process your User Information where the Processing is necessary in connection with any contract that you may enter into with us;
  * Compliance with applicable law: We may Process your User Information where the Processing is required by applicable law;
  * Vital interests: We may Process your User Information where the Processing is necessary to protect the vital interests of any individual; or
  * Legitimate interests: We may Process your User Information where we have a legitimate interest in carrying out the Processing for the purpose of managing, operating or promoting our business, and that legitimate interest is not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights, or freedoms.

### Legal Requests for Your Information

StudyBass may disclose your information or content to satisfy a law, regulation, legal process, governmental request, or governmental order. StudyBass' policy is to give you, advance notice if we are going to release your information unless by law we are prohibited from or advised against doing so. If we think that by disclosing your information we may prevent serious harm to StudyBass, its users, you, or anyone else for that matter, we may do so without notifying you. Finally, we may disclose your information if we believe it is necessary to detect, prevent, or otherwise address safety, fraud, or security concerns related to StudyBass.

### How Can Users Update, Correct or Delete Their Data?

Much of your data can updated and corrected in your [StudyBass User Account Settings](https://www.studybass.com/user/). Other User-Created Data may be updated and deleted through the same features where it was created by the user. Other data may be changed or deleted by request using the [website contact form](https://www.studybass.com/feedback/).

### Data Storage and Deletion of Accounts and Data

We are committed to protecting the security of your information. We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures designed to help protect your information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Despite these measures, you should know that we cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with information and mistakes may happen.

If you choose to delete or deactivate your account, you can no longer retrieve your content or reactivate your account, and we cannot do so for you. Also, your username may become available for another person to use.

StudyBass stores its data on servers run by third parties. We, or a third party we work with, may keep backups of StudyBass' data and code, which may or may not include your Personal Information and User-Created Data, even after you have deleted your account. Therefore, even after you delete your account, your data may remain in backups on our system, although it will be no longer visible or publicly accessible on the Site.

### International Transfers of Information

StudyBass hosts data with hosting service providers in the United States and Europe. The servers on which Personal Information is stored are kept in a controlled environment. While we take reasonable efforts to guard your Personal Information, no security system is impenetrable and due to the inherent nature of the Internet as an open global communications vehicle, we cannot guarantee that information, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others, such as hackers.

### Data Retention

StudyBass will retain Personal Information where we have an ongoing legitimate business or legal need to do so. Our retention periods will vary depending on the type of data involved, but, generally, we'll refer to these criteria in order to determine retention period:

  * Whether we have a legal or contractual need to retain the data.
  * Whether the data is necessary to provide our Services.
  * Whether our Members have the ability to access and delete the data within their StudyBass accounts.
  * Whether our Members would reasonably expect that we would retain the data until they remove it or until their StudyBass accounts are closed or terminated.

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your Personal Information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your Personal Information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your Personal Information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

### Children

StudyBass is not directed to individuals under 13. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will take steps to delete such information. If you become aware that a child has provided us with Personal Information, please contact us through the [website contact form](https://www.studybass.com/feedback/).

If a child under the age of 18 wishes to use the Site, he or she may not create an account. Instead, the child's parent or legal guardian must create an account in the parent's or legal guardian's name and guide and supervise their child's use of the Service.

### Your Rights Regarding to Your Personal Data under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are an individual in the European Economic Area (EEA), we collect and process information about you only where we have legal bases for doing so under applicable EU laws. This means we collect and use your information only where:

  * We need it to provide you the functionality of the Website, including to operate the Website, provide customer support and personalized features, and to protect the safety and security of the Website;
  * It satisfies a legitimate interest (which is not overridden by your data protection interests), such as for research and development, to market and promote the Website, and to protect our legal rights and interests;
  * You give us consent to do so for a specific purpose; or
  * We need to process your data to comply with a legal obligation.

If you have consented to our use of information about you for a specific purpose, you have the right to change your mind at any time, but this will not affect any processing that has already taken place. Where we are using your information because we or a third party have a legitimate interest to do so, you may have the right to object to that use though, in some cases, this may mean no longer using the Website. 

Additionally, once you have provided us your data, either actively or automatically, you will have the right to: 

  * Request access to the personal data we have from you;
  * Request a rectification, erasure, restriction of processing of your personal data;
  * Object to processing in certain circumstances;
  * Data portability to retain and reuse your personal data for your own purpose;
  * File a complaint with a supervisory authority if you believe that we have violated any of the rights concerning Personal Information about you. We encourage you to first reach out to us through the [website contact form](https://www.studybass.com/feedback/) so we have an opportunity to address your concerns directly before you do so.

### Conditions of Use and Notices

If you choose to visit our Website, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, application of the law of the State of Texas and venue for all disputes in Houston, Texas.

If any provision of this Privacy Policy, Cookie Policy or our Terms of Service is held invalid by a court of competent jurisdiction, the remainder of this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service will remain in full force and effect. 

### Updates to This Privacy Policy

From time to time this Privacy Policy will change. StudyBass will notify Users of any change to our Privacy Policy by posting the revised Privacy Policy with an updated date of revision on the Site. If any significant changes are made to the policy these will be called out with a short notice of the revision conspicuously posted on the Website. We may also contact Users and notify them of the changes if required by law.   
StudyBass values your privacy and will not change how any Personal Information already collected from Users is used in any material way without also providing notice of the change via email, through this Website, or through other means, and obtaining consent via your continued use to any new policies.
